<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Deep Learning | Academic</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/deep-learning/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/deep-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Deep Learning</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Deep Learning</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/deep-learning/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Файловая система FAT</title>
      <link>https://example.com/project/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/project/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Information in information systems (IS) arises in the process of processing stored data. On computers used to build ICs, data is stored in Read Only Memory (ROM) as named sequences called files. Storing files is like storing books in a library, and organizing access to them requires a special system that minimizes access time and provides convenience. The file system is a set of service structures on the media and operating system tools that provide file manipulation. (Historically, the operating systems of the Windows family have developed in two directions (Windows 95, Windows 98 and Windows Me are one direction, and Windows NT and Windows 2000 are the second direction), providing various means for working with service structures and files). The FAT (File Allocation Table) file system was developed by Bill Gates and Mark McDonald in 1977 and was originally used in the 86-DOS operating system. In order to achieve portability of programs from the CP/M operating system to 86-DOS, it retained the earlier restrictions on filenames. 86-DOS was later acquired by Microsoft and became the basis for MS-DOS 1.0, released in August 1981. This file system was originally designed to provide random access to files on relatively small floppy disks. There are currently four versions of FAT - FAT8, FAT12, FAT16 and FAT32. They differ in the bitness of records in the disk structure, that is, the number of bits allocated for storing the cluster number. FAT12 is mainly used for floppy disks, FAT16 for small disks, FAT32 for hard disks. Based on FAT, a new exFAT (extended FAT) file system was developed, which is used primarily for flash drives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;fat-structure&#34;&gt;FAT structure&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the FAT file system, the disk space of any logical drive is divided into two areas:
• system area and
• data area.
The system area is created and initialized when formatting, and subsequently updated when manipulating the file structure. The system area consists of the following components:
• the boot sector containing the boot record (boot record);
• reserved sectors (they may not exist);
• file allocation tables (FAT, File Allocation Table);
• Root directory (ROOT). These components are located on the disk one after another. The data area contains files and directories subordinate to the root. The data area is divided into so-called clusters. A cluster is one or more contiguous sectors of a data area. On the other hand, a cluster is the smallest addressable unit of disk space allocated to a file. Those. a file or directory occupies an integer number of clusters. To create and write a new file to disk, the operating system allocates several free disk clusters for it. These clusters do not have to follow each other. For each file, a list of all cluster numbers that are provided to this file is stored. Splitting a data area into clusters instead of using sectors allows you to:
• reduce the size of the FAT table;
• reduce file fragmentation;
• the length of file chains is reduced and access to the file is accelerated. However, a cluster size that is too large leads to inefficient use of the data area, especially in the case of a large number of small files (after all, an average of half a cluster is lost for each file). In modern file systems (FAT32, HPFS, NTFS) this problem is solved by limiting the cluster size (maximum 4 KB)
The map of the data area is the File Allocation Table (FAT). Each element of the FAT table (12, 16 or 32 bits) corresponds to one disk cluster and characterizes its state: free, busy or is a bad cluster.
• If the cluster is allocated to any file (ie, busy), then the corresponding FAT entry contains the number of the next file cluster;
• the last cluster of the file is marked with a number in the range FF8h - FFFh (FFF8h - FFFFh);
• if the cluster is free, it contains the null value 000h (0000h);
• an unusable (failed) cluster is marked with the number FF7h (FFF7h). Thus, in the FAT table, clusters belonging to the same file are linked in chains. The file allocation table is stored immediately after the boot record of the logical disk, its exact location is described in a special field in the boot sector. It is stored in two identical copies that follow each other. When the first copy of the table is destroyed, the second is used. Due to the fact that FAT is used very heavily when accessing a disk, it is usually loaded into the RAM (into the I / O buffer or cache) and remains there for as long as possible.
You can use the Disk Editor utility to view and edit the FAT table.
Detailed info
The information about the file itself is stored in another structure called the root directory. Each logical drive (The hard drive is a physical device, i.e. it can be physically installed, replaced or removed. For convenience, the hard drive is divided into logical drives that are virtual and cannot be touched, as they say. On one hard drive can be: • either several logical drives, • or a single logical drive.) has its own root directory (ROOT, English - root). The root directory describes files and other directories. The directory element is a file descriptor (descriptor). The descriptor of each file and directory includes it
• Name
• extension
• date of creation or last modification
• time of creation or last modification
• attributes (archive, directory attribute, volume attribute, system, hidden, read-only)
• file length (0 for directory)
• a reserved field that is not used
• number of the first cluster in the chain of clusters assigned to the file or directory; having received this number, the operating system, referring to the FAT table, will also find out all the other numbers of file clusters.
So, the user launches the file for execution. The operating system looks for a file with the desired name by looking at file descriptions in the current directory. When the required element is found in the current directory, the operating system reads the number of the first cluster of this file, and then determines the remaining cluster numbers from the FAT table. Data from these clusters is read into RAM, combined into one continuous section. The operating system transfers control to the file, and the program starts running.
You can also use the Disk Editor utility to view and edit the ROOT directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;varieties-of-fat&#34;&gt;Varieties of FAT&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The VFAT file system The VFAT (virtual FAT) file system first appeared in Windows for Workgroups 3.11 and was designed for protected mode file I/O. This file system is used by Windows 95. It is also supported by Windows NT 4. VFAT is the native 32-bit file system of Windows95. It is controlled by the VFAT.VXD driver. VFAT uses 32-bit code for all file operations and can use 32-bit protected mode drivers. BUT, the file allocation table entries remain 12- or 16-bit, so the disk uses the same data structure (FAT). Those. The VFAT table format is the same as the FAT format. VFAT supports long filenames along with &amp;ldquo;8.3&amp;rdquo; names. (VFAT is often said to be FAT with support for long names). The main disadvantage of VFAT is the large losses for clustering with large logical disk sizes and restrictions on the size of the logical disk itself.
FAT32 file system This is a new implementation of the idea of using the FAT table. FAT32 is the latest version of the FAT file system and an improvement on the previous version known as FAT16. It was created to overcome FAT16 volume size limitations while still allowing legacy MS-DOS programming code and preserving the format. FAT32 is a completely independent 32-bit file system. First used in Windows OSR2 (OEM Service Release 2). FAT32 is currently used in Windows 98 and Windows ME. It contains numerous improvements and additions over previous FAT implementations.
1. Much more efficient use of disk space due to the fact that it uses smaller clusters (4 KB) - it is estimated that it saves up to 15%.
2. Has an extended boot record that allows you to create copies of critical data structures, which increases the disk&amp;rsquo;s resistance to violations of disk structures
3. Can use a FAT backup instead of a standard one.
4. Can move the root directory, in other words, the root directory can be located in an arbitrary place, which removes the limit on the size of the root directory (512 elements, since ROOT was supposed to occupy one cluster).
5. The structure of the root directory has been improved. Additional fields have appeared, for example, creation time, creation date, last access date, checksum. There are still multiple descriptors for a long filename. exFAT An updated file system created by Microsoft to replace FAT32. Started in Windows Vista SP1 and has a maximum file size of 16 exabytes (EB), which is 1 EB = 1018 bytes. Compatible with Mac OS and Windows, it is a very good system for sharing large files. Cons: • It does not have any logging functionality, in which all changes to files on disk are logged before they are actually executed. • Not supported by Apple&amp;rsquo;s Time Machine. In a word, you will not be able to backup from Apple using Time Machine software. • Very complex structure requiring more computing power. Pros: • Rewrites the same sector fewer times&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
